<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Greg Zborovsky</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Greg Zborovsky</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 19:03:22 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My First Post and Expectations</title>
      <link>/posts/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 19:03:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>This post should give some ideas about what to expect from this website.
 About The about page will contain information about myself, but may not reflect newest events or changes.
 Blog I enjoy writing about technical topics, especially simple ones that grab my attention for maybe a week at a time. I am hoping to write up at least one post one per month.
 Projects This will be an organized place to list some of my projects, both completed and in progress.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CSE320 Vague Homeworks - Group Problem Solving Project</title>
      <link>/projects/problem-solving-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/problem-solving-project/</guid>
      <description>We noted that there are many local issues that students have the power to change. Working in a group with 3 other people, we noted that each of us were taking the same class, CSE320, systems fundamentals part 2. This class is one of the most difficult in Stony Brook University with hard material practical both in software engineering and in computer science theory. However, we found that roughly 95% of surveyed students found the homework documents difficult to understand and would have appreciated more information, clarification, and tips.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI-Enabled Provably Resilient Networked Microgrids - Press Release</title>
      <link>/projects/press-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2022 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/press-release/</guid>
      <description>This assignment had us choose a recent or future local event and write a press release on it. This assignment helped continue to develop the skill of concise, formal writing for other entities.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Install Python - User Instructions</title>
      <link>/projects/user-instructions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2022 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/user-instructions/</guid>
      <description>This class project tested my ability to write technical instructions for the average user. Specifically, I wrote about how an average user could install Python on their Windows computer. In the workplace, this will smoothly translate to writing comprehensible and clean documentation for both code and products.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linking With Linked Lists</title>
      <link>/posts/linking-with-linked-lists/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2021 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/linking-with-linked-lists/</guid>
      <description>Note: This is a post originally written and posted to my GitHub which I have moved here as of 4/23/2022.
Abstract Data structure courses often introduce linked lists as a basic data structure as an alternative to arrays. They supposedly have the advantage of constant time insertion and deletion at any point in the list as long as you have access to a pointer near the node you are inserting or deleting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Barnes–Hut CUDA Simulation</title>
      <link>/projects/nbody-simulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/nbody-simulation/</guid>
      <description>Intro An N-body simulation is a simulation of a system of n different particles or entities, typically simulating the force of gravity between them. From classic physics,
\[F=G\frac{m_1m_2}{r^2}\]
where F is force, G is the gravitational constant, \(m_1\) is the mass of object 1, \(m_2\) is the mass of object 2, and \(r\) is the distance between the centers of the two masses.
By applying this equation for every pair of entities and accumulating the results, we can calculate the force on every entity at any given point in time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ode to Binary Search</title>
      <link>/posts/ode-to-binary-search/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/ode-to-binary-search/</guid>
      <description>Note: This is a post originally written and posted to my GitHub which I have moved here as of 4/23/2022.
Introduction Given a sorted array, we can &amp;ldquo;binary search&amp;rdquo; through an array to find a certain element by comparing the middle element to our current element and then deciding either that we have found what we are looking for, that what we are looking for is in the left half of the array, or that what we are looking for is in the right half of the array.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chess Engine</title>
      <link>/projects/chess-engine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/chess-engine/</guid>
      <description>I wrote my first chess engine, which you can find on my GitHub.
I will be writing an updated version soon, but as a placeholder, I will note that writing a chess engine teaches you a treasure trove of information, especially if you are aiming to write a fast one. I will give a small preview of things I have learned and plan to learn:
 I better learned to program in C++, specifically about minimizing my memory and performance footprints.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Set Cover as Fast as Possible</title>
      <link>/projects/fast-minimum-set-cover/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2020 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/fast-minimum-set-cover/</guid>
      <description>Intro In the set cover problem, there exists a universe set U and a set S of subsets of U. The goal is to pick as few items of S as possible such that their union is equal to the set U.
This version of the problem, where we are trying to find the minimum number of elements of S such that their union is equal to S, is NP-hard. In practice, this means that this problem cannot be solved exactly nor verified efficiently.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple Platformer</title>
      <link>/projects/simple-platformer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2019 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/simple-platformer/</guid>
      <description>Intro Back in high school, for an AP CS final project, I decided to make a platformer where you can tell the character to jump by yelling. As a learning experience, I chose to write it in Processing, a piece of software that advertises itself as &amp;ldquo;a flexible software sketchbook&amp;rdquo; and separate language, but is actually a library for Java which makes it very easy to work with graphics, audio, and user input.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Hey! I&amp;rsquo;m a 2nd year student at Stony Brook University double majoring in Computer Science (CSE) and Applied Math and Statistics (AMS).
I&amp;rsquo;m primarily interested in the computer science side of things with math as a supporting factor. Right now, you&amp;rsquo;ll catch me learning about interesting algorithms (pssst scapegoat trees) and the basics of machine learning.
Outside of academics, you may find me exploring campus, walking, and hiking.
 Education  2nd year student at Stony Brook University studying Computer Science and Applied Mathematics and Statistics (Expected Graduation: May 2024) Relevant Courses: Honors Intro to Theory of Computation, Honors Analysis of Algorithms, Natural Language Processing, Systems Fundamentals I &amp;amp; II, Linear Algebra, Intro to Abstract Algebra, Multivariable Calculus, Differential Equations  Work Experience  Incoming Software Engineering Intern at Citadel (Summer 2022) Software Engineering Intern at Bloomberg L.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resume</title>
      <link>/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resume/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
